

Fabriciu Mendoza, MA

Software Engineer

+49 17682351102 • fabriciu.mendoza@gmail.com • linkedin/fabriciumendoza

• Angestrasse 29, Passau, Germany • Open to remote, hybrid, onsite

With 4+ years of experience as a Software Engineer, I am driven by a passion for continuous learning and innovation. I am adept at back-end, front-end, and database development. Throughout my professional journey, I have focused on collaborative development, specializing in building web applications and enhancing product quality through code optimization and proactive problem-solving.

Skills

Back-end:

Java, Springboot, Maven, REST APIs, JSON, XML, C++, Python, Java EE.

Database:

SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL, Server Reporting Services.

Front-end:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular.

Testing:

JUnit, Mockito, Postman, SoapUI.

Tools:

Visual Studio Code, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, NetBeans.

Methodologies:

Agile, Scrum.

Languages

English (C1)

German (A2)

Spanish (Native)

Interests

Cooking

Painting

Board games

Experience

Full Stack Developer

Infosys, Lima, Peru

09/2022 - 09/2023

- Migration of a legacy Java EE code to a modern Spring Boot and Angular architecture, using REST API microservices to enhance performance.
- Redesigned code to improve performance and reduce bugs.
- Implemented new features to enhance functionality and user experience.
- Conducted testing and code reviews to ensure high-quality deliverables.

Software Developer

07/2021 - 09/2022

Indra, Lima, Peru

- Developed a project from scratch using in a Mayen Java project.
- Enhanced system efficiency and reporting processes, contributing to improved security monitoring and risk management.
- Led a data extraction project, crafting SQL queries and scripts to process data from multiple systems, generating reports to identify security issues.

Software Developer

01/2021 - 06/2021

Synopsis, Lima, Peru

- Worked within an agile methodology on multiple projects focused on Java applications, addressing bug fixes and enhancing feature functionality.
- Contributed to the creation of new features based on user requirements and project needs, enhancing overall application performance.

Java Developer

11/2018 - 03/2020

Chain Service TI, Lima, Peru

- Contributed to the development and enhancement of Electronic Billing applications in Java with Spring Boot designed as microservices.
- Developed and maintained both REST and XML microservice APIs regarding billing declarations.
- Collaborated with the team to provide customer support, effectively addressing inquiries and resolving issues.

Education

Master in Computer Science

10/2023 - ongoing

University of Passau, Germany

Bachelor in Computer Science

03/2015 - 07/2019

Saint Ignatius of Loyola University, Lima, Peru